naturalgrocers.com 2017-03-12

# Privacy Policy | Natural Grocers

As used in this Privacy Policy, “Natural Grocers”, “us,” “we” and “our” refers to Natural Grocers by Vitamin Cottage, Inc. and its subsidiaries and affiliates.

Natural Grocers values the privacy of its customers’ information. This Privacy Policy describes how we acquire personal information through this Website, our mobile applications and our social media applications (collectively, this “Website”) and how we use, share and protect that information. By viewing this Website, you are consenting to the information collection, use and disclosure practices described in this Privacy Policy.

#### **IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU SHOULD NOT USE THIS WEBSITE.**

### **Types of Information Gathered**

We may obtain personal information from and about you in a number of different ways, including:

  1. Information that you give to us voluntarily while using a feature of this Website;
  2. When you purchase, order, return, exchange or request information about our products and services in our stores or on this Website;
  3. As described in the section titled “Cookies” below, or when you participate in interactive features of this Website;
  4. When you place online orders, purchase gift cards or participate on our customer engagement program;
  5. When you conduct a transaction where we collect information required by law (for example, age-restricted purchases);
  6. When you sign up for our e-mails, mobile messages, or social media notifications;
  7. When you register at a third party website, and provide personal information to such third parties, as we may (pursuant to agreements between Natural Grocers and those third parties) obtain such information to populate our registration forms for use when you hyperlink to this Website;
  8. When you enter a contest or sweepstakes; or
  9. When you send us email messages or call us by telephone (including when you provide us with comments, suggestions or other input).

During such activities, we may collect personal information about you that is not publicly available and can identify you, such as your name, mailing address, email address and phone number, birth date and financial information, such as credit card number.

##### Cookies

We use cookies to receive and store certain types of information (such as the pages you visit on this Website, which web address you came from, the type of browser/device/hardware you are using, search terms and IP-based geographic location) whenever you interact with this Website through your computer or mobile device. This information helps us customize your experience while visiting this Website and makes our marketing messages more relevant. You can opt out of IP-based geolocation web services at any time by changing your browser or device settings.

##### Hyperlinks

This Website may contain hyperlinks to third party websites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected at any such third party websites. Natural Grocers is not responsible for the privacy practices of such third party websites; by using this Website, you agree that such third party privacy practices may be significantly different than those stated in this Privacy Policy.

##### Registration

In order for you to receive certain benefits of this Website you may first be asked to register by supplying certain information. The more information you choose to share with us, the better we can craft our services to meet your needs.

##### Surveys and Polls

From time to time, users of this Website may be asked to participate in voluntary surveys and polls. As a part of this process, you may be asked to supply personal information, such as demographic information and lifestyle preferences. These surveys will be strictly voluntary and you can choose to disclose this information or not.

### **Use of Information**

We may use information gathered through this Website to: (i) provide services to you; (ii) administer our business activities; (iii) process, fulfill, manage and bill purchases, orders, payments, returns, exchanges and requests for information(including through third party merchandise and service suppliers); (iv) understand demographics and content preferences; (v) better serve you and other Natural Grocers customers: (vi)deliver coupons, mobile coupons, newsletters, promotions, new services, in-store messages, emails and text messages; (vii) send marketing communications and other information regarding our products, services and promotions; (viii) administer and improve this Website; (ix) conduct research and analysis, including focus groups and surveys; (x) administer sweepstakes and contests; (xi) provide notice of changes to this Website; (xii) prevent fraudulent transactions and monitor against theft;(xiii) provide information in connection with the sale, purchase, merger or reorganization of Natural Grocers; and(xiv) assist law enforcement, respond to subpoenas or disclose information when legally compelled to do so or when Natural Grocers, in good faith, believes that the law requires it or for the protection of our legal rights or those of a third party.

### **Sharing of Information**

We will not sell or otherwise share personally identifying information with third parties or nonaffiliated companies except for those purposes described above, or as required by law. However, we may share aggregate data collected through this Website that does not personally identify any party, and may from time to time share this type data with our business partners.

### **Information from Public Forums**

Any information you submit in a blog, chat room, social network or other public forum can be read, collected, or used by us and others, including, for example, to personalize your experience on this Website. You are responsible for the information you disclose in these forums and such information is not protected under this Privacy Policy.

### **Updating Personal Information**

You may change or access your personal information, or unsubscribe from any newsletters or promotional emails, just send us a message on our [contact us](https://www.naturalgrocers.com/contact-us/ "Contact Us") page.

### **Modifications**

**Natural Grocers reserves the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time, and such changes will be effective immediately upon being posted on this Website.** **YOUR CONTINUED USE OF THIS WEBSITE AFTER ANY SUCH MODIFICATION CONSTITUTES YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THE MODIFIED PRIVACY POLICY.** We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy from time to time for any changes.

### **Children’s Privacy**

This Website is not intended for the use by anyone under the age 18 years. Natural Grocers does not knowingly solicit and does not wish to receive any information from children.

### **Security**

We have attempted to take all reasonable steps to have physical, electronic and procedural safeguards in place to protect personal information gathered through this Website. This includes compliance with related federal regulations and may include use of industry-standard Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption to prevent any loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, or modification of personal information. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to or from our web sites, and you do so at your own risk.

### **Contact Us**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please [contact us](https://www.naturalgrocers.com/contact-us/ "Contact Us").

Last Updated: March, 2015
